hey guys today we're launching hip
Thruster 2.0 and I want to go over the
the new design for you guys so here I've
got the unit and it's still 16 in high
the dimensions are pretty similar uh
they haven't changed but uh the main
differences are the new this new band
Peg design and then the band pegs up
front so this lets you do banded
deadlifts and some other things and this
just lets allows for more versatility
with with hip thrusting which I'll go
over in a minute
so a few months back I was prescribing
banded deadlifts to my clients and it
was really a pain in the butt to set up
if you don't have a deadlift platform
and the deadlift platforms are very
expensive but I was using dumbbells to
keep the bands in place and it was just
seriously a a real pain in the butt to
to you know have dumbbells positioned on
each side of the barbell so you could
stretch a band over them and I had to
use you know really heavy heavy
dumbbells and lug them around
so that uh for that reason I'm like you
know we should have those the these band
pcks on our hip Thruster unit because
you're standing on the platform anyway
and actually our UK uh hip Thruster
they've been doing this actually all
along they thought of this before me um
the UK hip thrusters if you bought one
in the UK you already have this but uh
here you can see an action I just line
up and uh you know you can have mini
bands or you can use uh longer bands but
this works out really
well because at the top right here I
would guess that this adds you know just
with these mini bands this probably add
an extra 50
lbs and I like you start on the mat
because this is a little bit of a
deficit so you're combining a
like a 2in
deficit with the bands so it's really
you get an effect throughout the full
range of
motion so that's one huge benefit to the
new hip Thruster design is these
bands okay one advantage to the new
design was this this t uh band design is
that you can hook band packs you can
hook Loop two mini bands to this um you
know oriented perpendicular to the unit
and then you can perform banded barbell
hip thrust and this ends up being so
smooth and for most of my female clients
this is just ends up being the perfect
amount of resistance here to add to the
top so it's just a really smooth hip
thrust and if I had to guess I'd say
this probably adds around you know 40
lbs or so to the top of the hip thrust
if I used black bands it would probably
add you know 60 60 lbs or so but we also
like to do these with a mini band around
our knees or a hip Circle um that
actually is probably my favorite type of
hip thrust at the moment band mini band
or hip circle around the knees and then
two loops with the barbell it's really
really
smooth so let's say you don't even have
a barbell let's say you just want a hip
thrust out of your your own home and
store this you know at your in your in
your guest bedroom or in your closet or
in your garage well that's fine because
you can get an amazing workout just
using bands and
uh I like to do double banded hip thrust
so I can put a a band around my
knees
and I like to put
these just below the
knees and
for men we need a strong mini band um
the women can do well most women with
the you know just Loops from that you
can get from like perform better or
Power Systems I need stronger ones like
a hip Circle or this one is from X
bands.com this one gives me a really
good resistance and then this is what I
was talking about about this design it's
just so convenient here you just Loop it
on like this the old design had the pegs
going outwards so this you just Loop it
right here Loop it right here it's ready
to go I like to combine these two bands
because I'm stronger so you
just Loop another one on there and then
from here as you can
see I can get an amazing
workout from just using bands here
so I just did that for five reps if I
did this for a workout I'd probably do
three sets of 12 and uh you know it's a
really good strengthening effect on the
on the glutes and what I like about this
is that when you do barbell hit thrust
you tend to just like with squats you
tend to want to skip on your
depth with hip thrust you skip on your
bar height over time as you get stronger
you quit using full hip extension with
bands this gets it keeps that top range
strong and that's the Zone where you get
maximum glute activation at the very top
that's the highest your glutes can
activate is at the top of a hip thrust
so this keeps that range strong so then
if you also do barbell hip thrust you're
you're going to it's going to encourage
better form because you're going to
naturally be strong at that top range so
for that reason I encourage people who
have the ability to do both barbell and
band to do both of them throughout the
week but for people who just have hip
thrusters at their home I encourage them
to hip thrust 5 days a week and I think
you can get maximum results in the glute
Department doing hip thrust um different
types of hip thrust very frequently and
I've have a couple of test monals where
my clients saw really really good
results from doing just ban hip thrust
Alone 5 days per week